Guide to the Gleysteen Family Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Correspondence, Series I
  - Theodora Culver Gleysteen and William H. Gleysteen: family correspondence
    - To Mrs. Culver from Anne, Culver, WHG, TCG, Klazina on return trip to China and in Peking; to Gleysteens from Hsiao Chien; "Bulletin" Nos. 1, 2, 3, 1932 August 11- September 25 (Box 8, Folder 9)
      Enclosure: Truth Hall Chapel service bulletin, Sept. 23rd, 1932
    - To Mrs. Culver from TCG, WHG, Culver, Anne, Billy in Peking; "Bulletin" Nos. 4, 5, 6, 11, 12, 13, 14, 15; to Aunt Annie and Uncle Jim from Anne, 1932 October 1 - December 27 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - To Mrs. Culver from TCG, Culver, Klazina, WHG in Peking; "Bulletin" Nos. 16,17,18; "T.C.G.'s Bulletin January 1, 1933", 1933 January 1 - February 10 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - To Mrs. Culver from TCG, WHG, Anne in Peking; "Bulletin" Nos. 19, 20, 21 22, 23, 24, 25; to Messrs. Gimbel Brothers from TCG, 1933 February 12 - April 1 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - To Mrs. Culver from WHG, TCG, Anne in Peking; to Alice from TCG, WHG, 1933 April 2-23 (Box 8, Folder 13)
      Enclosures: "Personal Report of Theodora Culver Gleysteen April 1933";"Personal Report 1932-1933" by WHG; "The Common People's University"; "The Tinghsien Project"
    - To Mrs. Culver from TCG, WHG, Klazina in Peking; "Bulletin" Nos. 29, 30, 30, 31, 33, 34, 1933 May 7 - June 25 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - To Mrs. Culver from TCG, WHG, Klazina in Peking, Peitaiho; "Bulletin" No. 35; to Margaret from TCG at Peitaiho, 1933 July 2 - August 27 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - To Mrs. Culver from TCG, Culver, WHG, Alice, Klazina in Peking; "Bulletin" Nos. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 7, 1934 February 11 - April 1 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - To Mrs. Culver from TCG, Culver, WHG, Klazina in Peking; "Bulletin" No. 10, and four unnumbered bulletins, 1934 March 25 - May 20 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - To Mrs. Culver from TCG, WHG in Paotingfu, Peking, Peitaiho; to Mrs. Culver from TCG during hospital visit for Alice's appendicitis; three bulletins, 1934 May 27- June 30 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - To Mrs. Culver from WHG in Peking; to Mrs. Culver from TCG, Alice, Klazina, WHG in Peitaiho, 1934 July 8 - August 5 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - To Mrs. Culver from TCG, WHG, Anne, Klazina in Peking, 1934 August 12 - October 7 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - To Mrs. Culver from TCG, WHG, Anne, Billy, Culver in Peking; from Alice at Yenching University, 1934 October 14 - November 11 (Box 9, Folder 8)
      Enclosure: Armistice Day service bulletin, November 11
    - To Mrs. Culver from Alice, WHG, TCG, Billy, Klazina, Anne in Peking; "T.C.G.'s Bulletin"; "Bulletin" No.1, 1934 November 18 - December 30 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - To Mrs. Culver from TCG, Culver, WHG, Margaret in Peking; to Mrs. Culver from Theodore; "Bulletin" Nos. 2, 3, 4, 5, 1935 January 6 - February 17 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - To Mrs. Culver from Anne, Billy, TCG, WHG, Alice, Culver, Dirk, Klazina in Peking; to Mrs. Culver from Chi Pao Shih; "Bulletin" Nos. 6, 7, 9; receipt for Mrs. Culver from Truth Hall Press, 1935 February 22 - April 8 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - To Mrs. Culver from TCG, WHG, Billy at Peking, Shuntefu, 1935 April 14 - June 9 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - To Mrs. Culver from TCG, WHG, Anne in Peking, Petaiho, 1935 June 16 - July 26 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - To Mrs. Culver from WHG at S.S. Paowo; to Mrs. Culver from TCG, WHG, Anne, Billy in Peitaiho, Peking; to Mrs. Culver from Alice, 1935 July 28 - September 8 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - To Mrs. Culver from TCG, Culver, WHG, Anne in Peking; "Bulletin" Nos. 1, 2, 3, 1935 September 8 - October 20 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      Enclosure: "Visiting Peking Mosques"
    - To Mrs. Culver from WHG, TCG, Alice, Anne in Peking, 1935 October 27 - December 31 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      Enclosure: Christmas Program
    - To Mrs. Culver from Dirk, WHG, TCG, Klazina, Anne, Culver in Peking, 1936 January 6 - March 8 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - To Mrs. Culver from TCG, WHG, Klazina, Culver, Dirk in Peking, 1936 March 8 -1936 April 19 (Box 10, Folder 4)
      Enclosures: photos of East Cliff cottage, Peitaiho; obituary of Brigadier James Sansom; Program for International Children's Concert at the P.U.M.C. Auditorium, April 4; Peking Union Church bulletin for April 12
    - To Mrs. Culver from TCG, Culver, Klazina, WHG, Billy in Peking; to Mrs. Culver from TCG at Yenching University; to TCG from Klazina; to Gleysteens from Alice, 1936 April 26 - June 14 (Box 10, Folder 5)
      Enclosure: "Postscript"
    - To Mrs. Culver from TCG, Klazina, TCG, WHG, Anne, Margaret at Peking, Peitaiho, 1936 June 21 - August 2 (Box 10, Folder 6)
      Enclosure: "The Morton-(Alice)Gleysteen Wedding"
    - To Mrs. Culver from TCG, WHG, Anne, Culver, Klazina, Billy in Peitaiho, Peking, 1936 August 18 - September 20 (Box 10, Folder 7)
      Enclosure: Peking Union Church bulletin, September 20
    - To Mrs. Culver from TCG, WHG, Anne, Billy, Culver, Dirk in Peking; to Gleysteens from Alice, 1936 September 27 - November 8 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - To Mrs. Culver from TCG, WHG, Klazina, Margaret, Anne, Billy, Dirk in Peking, 1936 November 15 - December 27 (Box 10, Folder 9)
      Enclosure: Peking Union Church bulletin, November 29
    - To Mrs. Culver from Alice, Culver, WHG, TCG in Peking, Peitaiho, 1937 January 1 - September 12 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - To Mrs. Culver from TCG, Dirk, WHG, Billy Culver in Peking; to Theodore from WHG, 1937 September 19 - November 21 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - To Mrs. Culver from TCG, Dirk, WHG, Billy, Anne, Klazina in Peking, 1937 November 28 - December 27 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - To Mrs. Culver from WHG, Anne, TCG, Klazina, Dirk, Billy, Culver, Margaret in Peking; from TCG, WHG at Alice's home in Manchuria, 1938 January 2 - May 29 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - To Mrs. Culver from WHG, TCG, Billy, Culver, Anne in Peking, Peitaiho, 1938 June 3 - July 17 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - To Mrs. Culver from TCG, WHG, Culver, Dirk in Peitaiho, 1938 July 24 - August 22 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - To Mrs. Culver from Klazina, Anne, TCG, Culver, WHG, William Jr. in Peking; Bulletins: Nos. 1, 2, 1938 August 28 - September 18 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - To Mrs. Culver from Anne, WHG, TCG at Peking; to Mrs. Culver from Klazina; Bulletins: Nos. 4, 5, 6, 8, 1938 September 25 - November 7 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - To Mrs. Culver from Culver, WHG, TCG, William Jr., in Peking; Bulletins: Nos. 10, 12, 13, 15, 16, 1938 November - December 28 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - To Mrs. Culver from Billy, WHG, TCG, Culver, Klazina, Dirk in Peking; Bulletins Nos. 1, 2, 1939 January 1 - February 5 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - To Mrs. Culver from TCG, WHG, Culver, Dirk, Klazina in Peking; Bulletins Nos. 4, 5, 6, 7, 1939 February 11 - March 13 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - To Mrs. Culver from Klazina, WHG, TCG, Culver, Anne in Peking, Peitaiho; Bulletins: Nos. 8, 9, 1939 March 16 - April 30 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - To Mrs. Culver from TCG, WHG, William Jr., Culver in Peking; to Mrs. Culver from WHG, Culver in Edinburgh; Bulletins: Nos. 10, 11, 12, 1939 May 6 - June 19 (Box 11, Folder 9)
      Enclosures: Peking Union Church Baccalaureate Service bulletin, June 4, 1939; "Farewell Service in Honor of Miss Wright, Mr. and Mrs. Gleysteen and Graduating Classes, June 11th"
    - To Mrs. Culver from TCG, Culver, WHG, Alice en route to America (Berlin, Amsterdam, Edinburgh, Belfast), 1939 July 4-23 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - To Mrs. Culver from TCG, WHG in America, en route back to Peking, in Peking, 1940 July 21 - September 22 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - To Mrs. Culver from WHG, TCG, Bill, Dirk in Peking, 1940 September 29 - November 10 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - To Mrs. Culver from WHG, TCG, Bill, Dirk in Peking; includes: "Bulletin" Nos.12, 14, 1940 November 17 - December 29 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - To Mrs. Culver from WHG, TCG, Dirk, Billy in Peking; "Bulletin" Nos. 13, 15, 16, 1, 4, 6, 7, 8, 9, 1941 January 5 - March 9 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - To Mrs. Culver from WHG, TCG, Dirk in Peking; six bulletins, 1941 March 16 - May 11 (Box 11, Folder 16)
      Enclosure: "Personal Report of Wm. H. Gleysteen 1940-41"
    - To Mrs. Culver from WHG, TCG, Bill, Dirk in Peking, Peitaiho; to Mrs. Culver from TCG, Dirk at Peitaiho; four bulletins, 1941 May 18 - June 29 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - To Mrs. Culver from Billy, WHG, TCG in Peking, Peitaiho; three bulletins, 1941 June 29 - August 10 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - To Mrs. Culver from TCG at Peitaiho; two bulletins, 1941 August 17 - September 28 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - To Mrs. Culver from WHG, TCG, Dirk at Peking; to TCG, WHG from Mrs. Culver; two bulletins, 1941 October 5 - December 14 (Box 12, Folder 3)
      Enclosure: Peking Union Church October 5th service bulletin
    - To TCG, WHG from Mrs. Culver; to Mrs. Culver from TCG, WHG in Peking and in Rio de Janeiro en route to New York; to Culver, Klazina from TCG in Peking; to WHG from Culver in Peking, 1942 January 1 - November 14 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - To Mrs. Culver from TCG, WHG in the United States; TCG to/ from WHG; to Klazina from WHG at Kansas City; from Mrs. Culver to Gleysteens, 1944 January 4 - July 14 (Box 12, Folder 5)
      Enclosure: six page circular letter account of TCG and WHG's experiences in China from 1941 to 1943 during Japanese occupation of Peking, internment in Weihsien Internment Camp, repatriation on Gripsolm, return to U.S.
    - To Mrs. Culver from TCG, WHG in Silver Bay, NY, Jenkintown, PA, Arlington, VA; to Gleysteens from Mrs. Culver; to TCG from F.C. Sumner, 1944 July 16 - December 17 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - To WHG, TCG from Mrs. Culver; to Mrs. Culver from WHG, TCG at Arlington/Washington, D.C., 1945 January 4 - May 6 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - To Mrs. Culver from TCG, WHG in Jenkintown, New York City; to TCG from WHG at Washington, D.C., NYC; to Gleysteens from Mrs. Culver, 1945 May 24 - December 12 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - To Mrs. Culver from TCG. WHG at NYC, New Haven; to Gleysteens from Mrs. Culver, 1946 January 4 - July 18 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - To Mrs. Culver from TCG in NYC; to Gleysteens from Mrs. Culver; to TCG from WHG, 1946 July 20 -1947 March 22 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Family condolences and correspondence to TCG about WHG's death, 1948 January 17 - March 29 (Box 12, Folder 11)
      William Henry Gleysteen died January 18, 1948 in Jenkintown, PA
    - Condolences from non-family to TCG and family, 1948 January 18 - 23 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Condolences from non-family to TCG and family, 1948 January 24 - February 15 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Condolences, correspondence from non-family to TCG, Annie, 1948 February 15 - October 24 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - To Mrs. Culver, Helen from TCG during travels: to TCG from Mrs. Culver, 1948 August 18 - 1952 October 15 (Box 13, Folder 2)
      Trips included: 1948 (New York City, Nova Scotia, Newfoundland); 1950 (S.S. Pioneer Wave, South Carolina, Panama Canal, San Pedro California, Manila Philippines, Hong Kong, Istanbul Turkey, Island of Skye, Glasgow Scotland, Washington D.C.); 1952 (Southampton, London, Glasgow, Bad Godesberg Germany)
    - From TCG to her children after Mrs. Culver's death; undated letters from Mrs. Culver to TCG/Gleysteens, 1957 Dec 15, No date (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Theodora Culver Gleysteen and William H. Gleysteen: general correspondence
    - TCG from Junior Christian Endeavor Society, Helen Culin, Annie Heacock, Margaretta Selser, Ruth Wallerstein, 1900-1914 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Jenkintown Day Nursery: correspondence to/from Mrs. Culver and TCG; miscellaneous documents, 1903-1963 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - To TCG from, about Dr. Dripps of Bible Teachers Training School, NYC/The Stevens School, Germantown, PA, 1910-1913 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - To TCG from Culver grandparents (Andrew and Annie J. Culver), 1910-1911, no date (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - To TCG from, about missionaries and missions, pre-China, 1911-1917 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - During TCG's higher education: to/from friends, administrators while at school (Stevens School, Wilson College); acceptance letter from University of Pennsylvania, 1912-1917 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - To TCG from Caroline L. Palmer, Mary Angevine, Fanny Dayton of Bible Teachers Training School, 1912-1915, no date (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Re. Salvatore Terranova: correspondence between Dr. Wilbert W. White (president of Bible Teachers Training School) TBC, AWC, ST, 1913-1917 (Box 13, Folder 11-12)
    - Correspondence between Gleysteens and Board of Foreign Missions of Presbyterian Church USA, 1915-1956 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous letters from friends, family in America, 1918-1967, no date (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Re. financial matters of TCG, 1921-1941 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - To TBC, WHG from students and colleagues in China, 1922-1950 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - To TCG from Helen Scott, 1932-1949 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - From Cynthia Gleysteen Zwemer to Mrs. Culver, TCG, WHG, 1938-1947 (Box 13, Folder 18)
      Enclosures: newspaper obituaries of Cynthia
    - From relative Dirk Gleysteen to members of Gleysteen family, 1941-1954 (Box 14, Folder 1)
      Enclosure:obituary of Frances Steffens Gleysteen
    - Miscellaneous correspondence: to TCG, WHG, Mrs. Culver from friends, 1942-1969 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence to WHG, 1942-1947 (Box 14, Folder 3)
      Enclosures: promotional materials for speaking events
    - WHG: regarding Lincoln University presidency, 1945 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - To WHG, TCG from Andros, Lenke, 1945-1946 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Yu-Tang Lo of Truth Hall, Peking to/from WHG, TCG, Mrs. Culver, 1945-1948 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Re. Cynthia: letter from TCG to Gleysteen family; to WHG, TCG from Uncle Dirk; to WHG from R.L. Bosworth; undated letter from Cynthia to WHG, 1947 (Box 14, Folder 7)
      Enclosures: account of Cynthia's life, "Excerpt from a Letter to Yairda Pierson"
    - Correspondence between TCG and National Cyclopedia of American Biography about WHG biography, 1948-1949 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - To TCG from Ruth C. Wallerstein, 1948-1959 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - From TCG, AWC to/from various public officials, news reports about events and issues, 1952-1968 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, announcements, newspaper clipping, itinerary re. TCG selection as "Philadelphia Mother of the Year":, 1953 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, documents re. TCG civic work, including Health and Welfare Council; minutes of town meeting; letters to/from Borough Council, 1959-1967 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, documents re. TCG candidacy for Borough Council, 1963 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Annie Wallace Culver and Theodore B. Culver: family correspondence
    - To Theodore B. Culver (TBC) from siblings, father, 1868-1877 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - To TBC from sisters, parents, 1877-1881 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - To TBC from sister Annie and Anne J.S. Wallace (future wife), 1881-1885 (Box 16, Folder 3)
      Enclosure: invitation to wedding of Andrew Culver (TBC's father) and Ann Jane Skilton
    - To TBC from mother Ann; to/from cousin Annie (Anne J.S. Wallace); uncle Andrew, 1885-1886 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - TBC to/from Annie J.S. Wallace, 1886 September - 1887 May 13 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - TBC to/from Annie J.S. Wallace, 1887 May 13 - July 6 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - To Annie J.S. Wallace from TBC, aunt Annie, 1887 July 16 - August 6 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - To TBC from Annie J.S. Wallace; to AJSW from TBC's sister Annie Culver Boyd, aunt Annie, 1887 August 7-11 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - TBC to/from Annie J.S. Wallace; AJSW from aunt Annie, 1887 August 12-15 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - To Annie J.S. Wallace from TBC, aunt Annie, 1887 August 16-19 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - TBC to/from Annie J.S. Wallace, 1887 September 27 - October 17 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - TBC to/from Annie J.S. Wallace, 1887 October 30 - November 4 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - TBC to/from Annie J.S. Wallace, 1887 November 4-10 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - TBC to/from Annie J.S. Wallace, 1887 November 14 - December 30 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - TBC to/from Annie J.S. Wallace, 1887 November 6 - 1888 January 31 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - TBC to/from Annie J.S. Wallace, 1888 February 6-14 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - TBC to/from Annie J.S. Wallace, 1888 February 27 - March 12 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - TBC to/from Annie J.S. Wallace, 1888 March 14 - April 4 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - TBC to/from Annie J.S. Wallace, 1888 April 9 - May 1 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - TBC to/from Annie J.S. Wallace, 1888 May 3-21 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - TBC to/from Annie J.S. Wallace, 1888 May 23 - June 5 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - TBC to/from Annie J.S. Wallace; AJSW from uncle Andrew, aunt Annie, 1888 June 22 - October 4 (Box 17, Folder 9)
      Enclosure: invitation to wedding of Theodore B. Culver and Annie J.S. Wallace
    - Annie Wallace Culver (AWC, formerly Annie J.S. Wallace) to/from TBC; from niece, nephews, sister Mamie, 1890 August 6-14 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - AWC from niece, nephews, Mamie; TBC from father Andrew, AWC, 1890 August 15-1891 September 2 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - AWC from mother-in-law Ann J. Culver, sister-in-law, sister Marcie; to TBC from sister Katie, father Andrew, 1891 October 19-1892 November 3 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - AWC from mother-in-law Ann J. Culver, sister Margaret; to TBC from mother, 1893 May 16 -1894 May 2 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - To AWC from parents-in-law, 1894 May 7 - 1894 July 5 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - AWC from mother-in-law, sisters; to TBC from William Boyd, 1894 August 4 - 1895 January 28 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - AWC from parents-in-law, sisters,TBC, 1895 February 1 - August 26 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - AWC from mother-in-law, TBC, 1896 March 3 - 1897 August 5 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - AWC from TBC, "sister" Sallie, parents-in-law, 1897 August 10-1904 February 19 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - AWC from TBC, "sister" Kate Culver, sister Katie Wallace, granddaughter Gail; to TBC from father, siblings, 1904 February 20 - 1948, no date (Box 18, Folder 6)
      Enclosure: Christmas greetings from AWC and TBC
  - Annie Wallace Culver and Theodore B. Culver: general correspondence
    - TBC regarding business, from friends, 1842-1918 (Box 19, Folder 1)
      Enclosures: letter to TBC's sister Katie from niece Lizzie; bills, transit documents
    - TBC from C.H. Taylor, classmate at Boys Grammar School of Philadelphia (class of 1877):, 1879-1889 (Box 19, Folder 2-3)
    - TBC from and about Minnie from Lancaster: includes letters from sister Annie, Minnie, 1880-1882 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - AWC miscellaneous correspondence, 1887-1952 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - AWC from former servants, 1912-1946 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Letters regarding Theodora Culver Gleysteen, 1913-1922 (Box 19, Folder 7)
      Includes letter to Anna J. McKeag of Wilson College; to/from staff on Board of Foreign Missions of the Presbyterian Church in the U.S.A.; from Orlando A. and L.C. Mansfield of Wilson College; on TCG's wedding to WHG; on TCG's Westminster Guild Sketch
    - AWC from Cynthia Gleysteen Zwemer, 1919-1926 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - AWC from Elizabeth McCoy, 1919-1934 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - AWC from Helen Scott, 1920-1941 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - AWC regarding donations to organizations in Peking; includes letters from Clementine Bach, 1929-1954 (Box 19, Folder 11)
      Enclosures: account slips from The National City Bank of New York
    - AWC to/from Channing Pollock, 1943-1946 (Box 19, Folder 12)
      Enclosures: "Harvest of My Years"; newspaper obituaries of Pollock
    - Christmas Greetings from TBC and AWC, No date (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Klazina van der Linden Gleysteen Newell
    Klazina was the daughter of William H. and Theodora Culver Gleysteen.
    - Klazina to grandmother (Annie Wallace Culver) while at Westtown School, PA, 1940 November 17 - 1941 July 13 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Klazina to grandmother while at Westtown School, PA, and New Jersey College for Women, New Brunswick, 1941 July 20 - 1942 April 4 (Box 20, Folder 2)
      Includes letter to Mrs. Culver from H.B. Van Dyke of The Squibb Institute about Klazina's illness.
    - Klazina to grandmother while at Westtown School, PA, and New Jersey College for Women, New Brunswick, 1942 May 8 - December 10 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Klazina to grandmother, Aunt Mamie, parents from New Jersey College for Women and Presbyterian Hospital School of Nursing, Philadelphia, 1943 January 3 - 1944 December 16 (Box 20, Folder 4)
      Enclosures: grade reports October 4 and November 4, 1943
    - To Mrs. Culver, WHG, TCG from Bob Newell; to family from Klazina at Presbyterian Hospital School of Nursing, 1945 January 4 - 1946 March 17 (Box 20, Folder 5)
      Enclosure: engagement announcement news clipping of Klazina and Bob Newell
    - From Klazina to parents and grandmother from Presbyterian Hospital School of Nursing; from Bob to TCG, WHG, Mrs. Culver, 1946 March 9 - September 29 (Box 20, Folder 6)
      Enclosures: Commencement program and invitations to Presbyterian Hospital School of Nursing, April 1946; to TCG from Jennie R. Newell, Bob's mother; wedding announcement for Bob and Klazina
    - Klazina, Bob to parents, grandmother, 1946 October 3 - 1949 July 17 (Box 20, Folder 7-11)
    - Klazina, Bob to mother, grandmother, cousin Helen, 1947 July 21 - 1948 January 11 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Klazina, Bob to mother, grandmother, cousin Helen, 1950-1953 (Box 21, Folder 1-3)
    - Klazina, Bob to mother, grandmother; letters to Bob re. illness and death of Klazina, 1954-1958 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Undated correspondence from Klazina, No date (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Helen P. Scott
    Helen Scott was a close friend of the family who lived with Mrs. Culver and Theodora in later years.
    - Family correspondence: to Bill Scott, Mrs. Maurice Webster (from Helen and others), from TCG and WHG, 1941-1944 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Non-family correspondence: from friends Wang Shu Lin, Lena Boyd and regarding repatriation of US citizens from China aboard MS Gripsholm, 1934-1944 (Box 21, Folder 7)
- Diaries and Notebooks, Series II
  - Theodora Culver Gleysteen and William H. Gleysteen
    - Theodora Culver Gleysteen (TCG) diaries, 1906, 1907 (Box 22, Folder 1)
      Diaries are of the year-long type with daily entries.
    - TCG diary, 1908 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - TCG diary, 1909 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - TCG diary, 1910 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - TCG diary, 1911 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - TCG diary, 1912 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - TCG diary, 1913 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - TCG diary, 1914 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - TCG diary, 1915 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - TCG diary, 1916 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - TCG diaries, 1917, 1918, 1919 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - TCG diaries, 1920, 1921, 1922 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - TCG diaries, 1923, 1924, 1925 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - TCG diaries, 1926, 1927 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - TCG diaries, 1928, 1929 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - TCG diaries, 1930, 1931, 1932 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - TCG diaries, 1933, 1934, 1935 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - TCG diaries, 1936, 1937 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - TCG diaries, 1938, 1939 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - TCG diaries, 1940, 1941, 1942 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - TCG diaries - two volumes both describing repatriation on SS Gripsholm, 1943 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - TCG diaries and daily planners (one of each for both years), 1944, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - William H. Gleysteen (WHG) diary, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - TCG notebook containing notes on books, speeches, etc., 1945-1946 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - TCG diaries and daily planners, 1947, 1948 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - WHG notebooks containing notes about books read, circa 1947-1948 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - TCG diaries and daily planners, 1948, 1949 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - TCG diary/notebook containing records of mail received and responses, contact information of others, and trip notes, 1948-1956 (Box 27, Folder 2)